<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bright Path Strong</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 18:43:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/cropped-bps-site-icon-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Bright Path Strong</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Justice for Jim Thorpe! Olympic Wins Fully Reinstated by IOC on 110th Anniversary</title>
		<link>/justice-for-jim-thorpe/</link>
					<comments>/justice-for-jim-thorpe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chris Nielsen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SALT LAKE CITY, July 15, 2022 &#8211; The International Olympic Committee (IOC) reinstates Jim Thorpe as the sole champion of the decathlon and pentathlon in the 1912 Olympic Games.&#160; For 110 years, advocates for the Sac and Fox and Potawatomi athlete, including two American Presidents, have urged the IOC to reinstate Jim Thorpe as the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image alignfull size-large is-style-default"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="538" src="/wp-content/uploads/Honors-Restored-1024x538.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-518" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Honors-Restored-1024x538.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/Honors-Restored-300x158.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/Honors-Restored-768x403.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/Honors-Restored.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><strong>SALT LAKE CITY, July 15, 2022 &#8211;</strong> The International Olympic Committee (IOC) reinstates Jim Thorpe as the sole champion of the decathlon and pentathlon in the 1912 Olympic Games.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For 110 years, advocates for the Sac and Fox and Potawatomi athlete, including two American Presidents, have urged the IOC to reinstate Jim Thorpe as the sole champion in his events. Bright Path Strong (BPS) <a href="http://www.brightpathstrong.org/">www.brightpathstrong.org</a> is honored to have played a part in removing this injustice that tarnished Thorpe’s enduring legacy.</p>



<p>IOC President, Thomas Bach, said: “Thanks to the great engagement of Bright Path Strong a solution could be found.&nbsp;This is a most exceptional and unique situation. It is addressed by an extraordinary gesture of fair play from the concerned National Olympic Committees.”</p>



<p>Anita Thorpe, granddaughter of Jim Thorpe, Vice Chairman/Sac and Fox Gaming Commission,&nbsp; and BPS Honorary Board Member, proclaimed: “A moment 110 years in the making to finally hear the words officially spoken again, &#8216;Jim Thorpe is the sole winner of the 1912 decathlon and pentathlon.&#8217; A glorious time of celebrations to all of his friends, family, and supporters. Hooray!!!&#8221;</p>



<p><strong>Honors Restored</strong></p>



<p>Bright Path Strong commends the IOC for setting the record straight and fully reinstating Jim Thorpe. “We are so grateful this nearly 110-year-old injustice has finally been corrected, and there is no confusion about the most remarkable athlete in history,” said Nedra Darling, BPS co-founder and citizen of the Prairie Band Potawatomi Nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In 1913, the IOC wrongfully stripped Jim of his wins after it was revealed that he played minor league baseball prior to the 1912 Summer Games, declaring he had infringed the rules regarding amateurism in place at the time. In 1982, the IOC returned replica gold medals to the Thorpe family and designated him a co-champion in the official records, though he dominated the competition, and his opponents only reluctantly accepted the gold medals reallocated to them.</p>



<p>Dennis Hendricks, council member of Tuolumne Band of Me Wuk Indians and BPS Board Member said, “Jim Thorpe faced seemingly insurmountable odds on and off the field. He represented this country before it even recognized Native Americans as citizens but he never gave up. He was an inspiration then and he is an inspiration now. Today is yet another victory for this great hero.”</p>



<p><strong>A Team Effort</strong></p>



<p>On July 15, 2020, Bright Path Strong and its Tribal partners launched a major campaign to right the greatest injustice in Olympic history and have Jim Thorpe reinstated as the sole champion in his events. This included an online petition and support from National Congress of American Indians, Native American Rights Fund, National Native Boarding School Coalition, Indian Gaming Association, Native American Finance Officers Association, Amateur Athletic Union, Pro Football Hall of Fame, The Doug Williams Center, and the unprecedented efforts of IOC Representative to the U.S., Ms. Anita DeFrantz, who became an ally after learning how Thorpe was wrongfully stripped of his gold medals while a student at Carlisle Indian Industrial School where he “survived an education designed to rob him of his culture.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>“This was made possible by supporters from Indian Country and from around the world,” said Chris Taylor, citizen of the Chitimacha Tribe of Louisiana and BPS co-founder. “This could not have been accomplished without our Tribal partners: Tuolumne Band of Me Wuk Indians, Chicken Ranch Rancheria Me-Wuk Indians of California, Tonto Apache Tribe, The Mohegan Tribe, Sealaska, Yocha Dehe Wintun Nation, Bear River Band of the Rohnerville Rancheria, and Shingle Springs Band of Miwok Indians.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Chairman Lloyd Mathiesen of Chicken Ranch Rancheria said, “We are excited this injustice has finally been corrected and are proud to be a part of changing history and helping tell Jim’s story. Jim’s resilience and perseverance stands as a beacon to our youth and shows them anything is possible.”</p>



<p>Nedra Darling concludes, “I pray that Jim, his family, and our ancestors are celebrating that the truth has been upheld today, on this 110th anniversary of Jim being awarded his Olympic gold medals. This is a day for great celebration.”</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>We&#8217;re not finished! Bright Path Strong&#8217;s mission is to continue Jim Thorpe&#8217;s legacy of community service, and that is just what we are going to do. Please continue to support Bright Path Strong by donating today. </em></strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-image is-style-default"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.paypal.com/donate?token=5yyIt431Rm_6JYlS0PWoYiIniCK5lgdZarbazIszxookVw4QzutAIkHxJ1m7HhWHFiy0J0ZtZAZPswLR"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/donate-hostedbutton-paypal-edited.png" alt="Donate Today!" class="wp-image-539" width="260" height="113" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/donate-hostedbutton-paypal-edited.png 468w, /wp-content/uploads/donate-hostedbutton-paypal-edited-300x131.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 260px) 100vw, 260px" /></a></figure></div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/justice-for-jim-thorpe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Protected: Downloads</title>
		<link>/downloads/</link>
					<comments>/downloads/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chris Nielsen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 21:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is no excerpt because this is a protected post.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<form action="/wp-login.php?action=postpass#038;wpe-login=true" class="post-password-form" method="post">
<p>This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:</p>
<p><label for="pwbox-501">Password: <input name="post_password" id="pwbox-501" type="password" spellcheck="false" size="20" /></label> <input type="submit" name="Submit" value="Enter" /></p>
</form>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/downloads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Protected:</title>
		<link>/who-is-jim-thorpe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Chris Nielsen]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 18:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jim]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is no excerpt because this is a protected post.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<form action="/wp-login.php?action=postpass#038;wpe-login=true" class="post-password-form" method="post">
<p>This content is password protected. To view it please enter your password below:</p>
<p><label for="pwbox-355">Password: <input name="post_password" id="pwbox-355" type="password" spellcheck="false" size="20" /></label> <input type="submit" name="Submit" value="Enter" /></p>
</form>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Live Event: Native American Olympic Stories</title>
		<link>/live-event-native-american-olympic-stories/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brtpathstrong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 22:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Join us for this special live Zoom roundtable with Olympic Gold Medalist Billy Mills &#38; Jim Thorpe Biographer Robert Wheeler, in a conversation led by Nedra Darling, co-founder of Bright Path Strong. Thursday, Feb 25th 2PM EST / 11AM PST Meet the Panelists: Billy Mills Billy Mills was born on June 30, 1938 in Pine [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="536" src="/wp-content/uploads/Huntsman-Senior-Games_03.2-1024x536.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-323" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/Huntsman-Senior-Games_03.2-1024x536.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/Huntsman-Senior-Games_03.2-300x157.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/Huntsman-Senior-Games_03.2-768x402.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/Huntsman-Senior-Games_03.2-1536x804.jpg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/Huntsman-Senior-Games_03.2.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Join us for this special live Zoom roundtable with Olympic Gold Medalist Billy Mills &amp; Jim Thorpe Biographer Robert Wheeler, in a conversation led by Nedra Darling, co-founder of Bright Path Strong.</p>



<p><strong>Thursday, Feb 25th 2PM EST / 11AM PST</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_AD3g6gIMRHGSqOwxCszYBw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">REGISTER NOW</a></div>
</div>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Meet the Panelists:</strong></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong><strong>Billy Mills</strong></strong></h3>



<p>Billy Mills was born on June 30, 1938 in Pine Ridge, South Dakota. He is Oglala Lakota (Sioux) and grew up on the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation. Billy did not have an easy childhood. Surrounded by poverty and orphaned at the age of 12, he started running to channel his energy into something positive. In high school, his gift for running become more apparent as he set records in numerous track events. He went on to earn a track scholarship from the University of Kansas and then served as an Officer in the United States Marine Corps. At the 1964 Olympics, he shocked the world and came from behind to win the gold medal in the 10,000 meters race. At the time, he set a world record of 28 minutes, 24.4 seconds and is still the only American to ever win a gold medal in the 10 m event. His win was an upset that has been called the second greatest moment in Olympic history. In Lakota culture, someone who achieves great success has a ‘giveaway’ to thank the support system of family and friends who helped him achieve his goal. As part of his effort to give back to his community, Billy helped found <a href="https://indianyouth.org/">Running Strong for American Indian Youth</a> and became the organization’s National Spokesperson. Today Billy travels over 300 days every year. He visits Native American communities throughout the U.S. and speaks to youth about healthy lifestyles and taking pride in their heritage.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Robert Wheeler</strong></h3>



<p>Emmy Award-winner Bob Wheeler co-founded the Jim Thorpe Foundation with his wife, Dr. Florence Ridlon. Jim&#8217;s son, Lt. Colonel Carl Phillip Thorpe, was insistent that full credit for the International Olympic Committee&#8217;s decision to restore his father&#8217;s gold medals be given to &#8220;Bob and Florence, who even put their own careers aside for it.&#8221; The editor of PRO, the official magazine of the National Football League, reviewed Bob&#8217;s biography of Jim as the &#8220;definitive volume on Thorpe.&#8221; Bob is an Executive Producer for the upcoming feature film about Jim Thorpe, Bright Path, which is based on his book, Jim Thorpe: World’s Greatest Athlete. Bob&#8217;s career includes managing public relations for ABC Sports, FOX Sports, and the White House Conference for Children and Youth as well as forming his and his wife’s public relations company, Wheeler/Ridlon Communications.</p>



<p><strong>Moderator:</strong></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Nedra Darling</strong></h3>



<p>Nedra Darling, a citizen of the Prairie Band Potawatomi Nation and a proud Cherokee Nation descendent, co-founder of Bright Path Strong and an executive producer of the forthcoming feature film Bright Path. She co-produced the award winning documentary Surviving Columbus while director of the nation’s first American Indian Film and Video center at the Institute of American Indian Arts. Nedra devoted her 35 year federal government career to celebrating and uplifting American Indian and Alaska Native peoples and continues her work for Indian Country by telling our truths in movies.</p>



<p><strong><em>About Bright Path Strong</em></strong></p>



<p>Bright Path Strong was created to share and amplify authentic Native American voices and stories, past and present. Representation matters, and it’s time we shine a light on our real history, our people, and our resilience — in our own words.</p>



<p>The right path is the Bright Path.</p>



<p></p>



<p><strong><em>About <a href="https://indianyouth.org/">Running Strong</a></em></strong></p>



<p>Billy Mills (right) joined forces with Eugene Krizek (left) in 1986 to help found Running Strong for American Indian Youth®. Running Strong was founded under Christian Relief Services in 1986. After Billy Mills (Oglala Lakota) became the Olympic champion for the 10K, he made it his priority to give back to his community and create a better future for Native American youth.</p>



<p><strong>Our Tribal Partners:</strong></p>



<ul><li>The Tuolumne Band of Mewuk Indians</li><li>The Mohegan Tribe</li><li>Yocha Dehe Wintun Nation</li><li>The Tonto Apache Tribe</li><li>The Bear River Band of the Rohnerville Rancheria</li><li>Chicken Ranch Rancheria of Mewuk Indians of California</li><li>Sac &amp; Fox Nation</li><li>Sealaska Corporation</li><li>Shingle Springs Band of Miwok Indians</li></ul>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_AD3g6gIMRHGSqOwxCszYBw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">REGISTER NOW</a></div>
</div>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Live Event: What is the Earth Telling Us Right Now?</title>
		<link>/live-event-what-is-the-earth-telling-us-right-now/</link>
					<comments>/live-event-what-is-the-earth-telling-us-right-now/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brtpathstrong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 06:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://brightpathstrong.local/?p=228</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Join us for this special live Zoom roundtable with environmental scientist and Absentee Shawnee &#38; Kickapoo tribe member Paulette Blanchard, and Faithkeeper of the Turtle Clan of the Seneca Nations of the Iroquois Confederacy Oren Lyons in a conversation led by a member of the Grammy Award-winning band Portugal. The Man. Thursday, Dec 10th 2 [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image alignwide size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="557" src="/wp-content/uploads/3311A01B-4797-4DEF-950F-F3D9B410B727-1024x557.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-229" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/3311A01B-4797-4DEF-950F-F3D9B410B727-1024x557.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/3311A01B-4797-4DEF-950F-F3D9B410B727-300x163.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/3311A01B-4797-4DEF-950F-F3D9B410B727-768x418.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/3311A01B-4797-4DEF-950F-F3D9B410B727-1536x835.jpeg 1536w, /wp-content/uploads/3311A01B-4797-4DEF-950F-F3D9B410B727-2048x1114.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Join us for this special live Zoom roundtable with environmental scientist and Absentee Shawnee &amp; Kickapoo tribe member Paulette Blanchard, and Faithkeeper of the Turtle Clan of the Seneca Nations of the Iroquois Confederacy Oren Lyons in a conversation led by a member of the Grammy Award-winning band Portugal. The Man.</p>



<p><strong>Thursday, Dec 10th 2 pm EST | 11 am PST</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://us02web.zoom.us/webinar/register/4916059396053/WN_oVz-Jh67QZueDgSMNDInYw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">REGISTER NOW</a></div>
</div>



<p></p>



<p><strong>Meet the Panelists:</strong></p>



<p><strong>Chief Oren Lyons</strong></p>



<p>International Human Rights Advocate, Environmental Activist Oren Lyons is a Faithkeeper of the Turtle Clan and serves as a Member Chief of the Onondaga Council of Chiefs and the Grand Council of the Iroquois Confederacy, the Haudenosaunee Peoples. He has been active in international Indigenous rights and sovereignty issues for over four decades at the United Nations and other international forums. In addition to his many accolades for extraordinary achievements, Oren holds a Juris Doctorate of Law from Syracuse University and is the recipient of the prestigious Rosa Parks and George Arents Awards for environmental and social activism, as well as the Green Cross International Environmental Icon Award (2019).</p>



<p><strong>Paulette Blanchard&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Paulette Blanchard, Absentee Shawnee &amp; Kickapoo, is a current PhD candidate in the department of Geography at the University of Kansas, and a 2018-2020 Diversity and Inclusion Fellow with the University of Corporation for Atmospheric Research. Her current work addresses Indigenous science, Indigenous led environmental movements and activism for Indigenous Peoples and other intersectional and marginalized populations. Paulette holds a Master of Arts in Geography from the University of Oklahoma and a Bachelor of Arts in Indigenous &amp; American Studies from Haskell Indian Nations University.</p>



<p><strong>Moderator:</strong></p>



<p><strong><a href="https://www.ptmfoundation.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Portugal. The Man</a></strong></p>



<p>Portugal. The Man is a Grammy Award-winning rock band from Wasilla, Alaska, currently based in Portland, Oregon. Recipients of the Public Sector Leadership Award from the National Congress of American Indians (NCAI) and Legend Award from the Native American Music Awards, the band is widely recognized for their activism and advocacy for Indigeous rights. A Portugal. The Man show always opens with a land acknowledgement ceremony, and in July of 2020, they announced the launch of the PTM Foundation, an organization “focused on building community resilience, empathy, and awareness through music, stories, art, education and connectivity.”</p>



<p><strong>About Bright Path Strong:&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Bright Path Strong was created to share and amplify authentic Native American voices and stories, past and present. Representation matters, and it’s time we shine a light on our real history, our people, and our resilience — in our own words.</p>



<p>The right path is the Bright Path.</p>



<p><strong>Our Tribal Partners:</strong></p>



<ul><li>The Tuolumne Band of Mewuk Indians</li><li>The Mohegan Tribe</li><li>Yocha Dehe Wintun Nation</li><li>The Tonto Apache Tribe</li><li>The Bear River Band of the Rohnerville Rancheria</li><li>Chicken Ranch Rancheria of Mewuk Indians of California</li><li>Sac &amp; Fox Nation</li><li>Sealaska Corporation</li><li>Shingle Springs Band of Miwok Indians</li></ul>



<div class="wp-block-buttons is-layout-flex wp-block-buttons-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-button"><a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://us02web.zoom.us/webinar/register/4916059396053/WN_oVz-Jh67QZueDgSMNDInYw" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">REGISTER NOW</a></div>
</div>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/live-event-what-is-the-earth-telling-us-right-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet Jim Thorpe, a Real-Life Native American Superhero</title>
		<link>/meet-jim-thorpe-a-real-life-native-american-superhero/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[brtpathstrong]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 03:56:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brightpathstrong.local/?p=178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Get to know a true G.O.A.T. Jim Thorpe, a.k.a. Wa-Tho-Huk (meaning Bright Path) was a Native American athlete, actor, and humanitarian who dominated in nearly every sport he played, despite all odds. At the 1912 Olympics in Sweden, he brought home two gold medals for the United States — one for the pentathlon and one [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Get to know a true G.O.A.T.</h3>



<p>Jim Thorpe, a.k.a. <em>Wa-Tho-Huk</em> (meaning Bright Path) was a Native American athlete, actor, and humanitarian who dominated in nearly every sport he played, despite all odds. At the 1912 Olympics in Sweden, he brought home two gold medals for the United States — one for the pentathlon and one for the decathlon. He broke records at the events and was proclaimed &#8220;World’s Greatest Athlete&#8221; by King Gustav the V.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many talk about his athletic strength, but few highlight his resilience. Ahead of the games, Jim Thorpe’s shoes were stolen but instead of giving in, he scoured the area grabbing two mismatched shoes from two different garbage cans. Despite the challenge, he went on to take the gold.</p>



<p>The setbacks didn’t end there, however. About six months after he won, the International Olympic Committee (IOC) stripped Jim of his rightfully earned medals and champion status. He was heartbroken, but not defeated.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p><em>Decades after his passing, a petition carrying 1 million signatures calling for a reversal of the decision that had cheated Jim Thorpe out of his Olympic wins was delivered to the IOC, and his medals were restored. This chapter in Jim’s story should end there, but the fight continues to this day. </em></p><cite>Learn why <a href="https://petition.brightpathstrong.org/">Bright Path Strong has petitioned the IOC</a> to restore the records</cite></blockquote></figure>



<p>Jim wasn’t just an Olympic gold champion, though. He went on to become a pro athlete in both football and baseball. He always played the game with a higher purpose, and went on to coach football, and was even elected as the first President of the NFL.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="BRIGHT PATH STRONG presents: Jim Thorpe -- The World&#039;s Greatest Athlete" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cwX5DPsLY8k?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Living through two World Wars, the Spanish Flu, and the Great Depression, Jim’s continued resilience became an asset as he set his sights on a new career path: acting. And in true Bright Path style, it wasn’t really about being in the spotlight — it was about bringing real Native representation to the big screen.</p>



<p>As his hard-earned athletic fame opened doors for him in Hollywood, Jim would get calls late at night about helping out fellow Native Americans looking for work. With the help of Cecelia Blanchard, Jim co-founded the Indian Center, later named the Native American Actors Guild, helping hundreds of Native people to secure jobs in TV and cinema.</p>



<p>It’s no wonder that he earned the nickname &#8220;Akapamata,&#8221; meaning &#8220;Caregiver&#8221; in Sac &amp; Fox. There are countless stories about Jim’s tireless work to lend a hand to folks in Native communities across the US.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Akapamata" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U5tUD2Uj3Yk?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>For Jim, it wasn’t just about being recognized as a champion athlete or a movie star. It was about using his celebrity status to amplify Native American stories that needed to be told. Thorpe didn’t just give 100% when playing sports — he gave it his all when caring for his people, too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that’s why, all these years later, it’s so important to keep his legacy alive and continue to share Native American stories of resilience and strength.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jim has taught us that whatever you’re after, keep going.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
